《速度与激情3：东京漂移》
车不错
Nice ride.
用来干活的
It does the job.
什么活 送披萨么
What job, delivering pizzas?
好吧 其实跟车没关系 还是开车的人重要
Well, it's not the ride, it's the rider.
- 怎么回事 - 什么
- What the hell was that? - What?
嘿 你和我的妞搭讪吗
Hey! You talking to my girl?
- 卧槽 我们赶上好戏了 - 那可不
- Oh, shit. Here we go. - Yeah.
她只是夸了夸我的车
She was just admiring my ride.
“我的车”
"My ride."
我奶奶的别克都比那破烂车强
My grandma's Buick could smoke that piece of shit, trailer trash.
好吧 那你爹的道奇蝰蛇车呢
Well, what about your daddy's Viper?
这可是五百马力 还配备博拉排气系统的
This beast's got 500 horsepower and a Borla exhaust system.
起步到60只需要4.3秒
It does 0 to 60 in like 4.3 seconds...
- 说的对 - 对对
- That's about right. That's about right. - Yeah.
哇哦 你还看得懂说明书呐
Wow. You can read the brochure.
干得漂亮 扔得好啊
What a pitch, baby. What a pitch. I like that.
他要干啥
What's he gonna do?
- 我们上啊 - 来吧
- Let's make it happen. - Bring it.
没事儿 我在呢
I got your back.
你们为什么不让车来说话
Why don't you nice boys let your cars do the talking?
有奖励我才参加比赛
I only race for pink slips.
我这车八万美元
This car goes for 80 grand.
我为什么要和那烂车比赛
What would I do with a broken-ass piece of shit like that?
我来做奖品怎么样
How about me?
我跟胜者走
Winner gets me.
快剪断 快走 走走走
Cut it, let's out it. Let's go, go, go, go!
别手软啊
Blast-off, baby!
先跑完一圈的人胜利
First one out the other side...
- 是时候了 - 来吧
- It's time. - Let's go!
- 准备好了吗 小伙子们 - 干漂亮点 克莱
- Ready, boys? - Make it interesting, Clay.
我靠
Shit!
耶
Yeah!
我以为你很爱我呢
I thought you loved me.
噢 完了
Oh, Well.
怎么回事
What the hell?
看来毕业舞会我有新舞伴了
Guess I got a new date for prom.
- 克莱 停车 - 闭嘴
- Clay, stop the car! - Shut up!
- 克莱 停车啊 - 闭嘴
快停车
Stop it!
克莱 求求你了 停车好吗
Clay, please stop! Please stop!
我能拷一份那个吗
Can I get a copy of that?
以为这很好玩吗
You think this is a joke, huh?
你看看那边的芭比和她男朋友
You see Ken and Barbie over there?
他们从这儿出去的时候连根毫毛都不会少
They're gonna walk out of here without even a slap on the wrist.
他们父母早就把关系打通了
Mommy and Daddy are too hooked up.
但是我喜欢你这样的小蠢蛋
But I like screw-ups like you.
知道为什么吗 因为你百分之百有罪
You know why? 'Cause you're 100% guaranteed conviction.
- 我的车呢 - 我碾碎了
- Where's my car? - I crushed it.
你说什么
You did what?
- 坐下 你完了 - 冷静 小伙子
- Sit down! You're done. - Easy, easy.
你完了 听懂了吗 你完了
You're done. You understand me? You're done.
在你成人之前一切都完了 给我坐下
And all before your eighteenth birthday. Now sit down.
肖恩
Sean.
你脑子里都在想些什么
What the hell were you thinking, huh?
博斯韦尔夫人 请坐
Mrs. Boswell? Please.
其实
It's, um...
我是单身
It's Miss.
警官 在这里抽烟不违法吧
Officer, is it illegal to smoke in here?
情况不太妙 案情已经很明显了
It's a tough state. And it's a pretty clear-cut case.
他还算走运 因为是未成年人
He'll be lucky if they don't try him as an adult.
两年里面我们都搬了三次家了
This is our third town in two years.
你儿子之前有过两次
Your son's got two priors for reckless driving,
不顾后果的飙车行为
willful destruction of property.
这是第三次了
This makes it strike three.
他以后肯定会被禁止开车
They're definitely gonna want to get him off the streets.
肯定还能有别的方法解决
Well, there's just got to be another way.
这次我们要搬到哪儿
So, where are we moving this time?
不是我们要搬家
We are not moving anywhere.
肖恩
Sean.
我以为你七号才到呢
I thought you were gonna be here on the 7th.
今天就是七号了
Today is the 7th.
好吧 你在这等我一下
Well, look, just hold on one second.
进来吧
Come on in.
就是这儿了
This is it.
肖恩 我本来是要去接你的
You know, Sean, I was gonna be there.
但是你妈妈 她说你七号才能到
But your mom, she said the 7th, see,
日本的时差是提前一天
and we're a day ahead of you in Japan.
好吧 还好你已经到了
Well, you're here now, and that's good.
你妈妈还好吗
So, how is your mom?
我睡哪儿
Where do I sleep?
肖恩 你要明白她别无选择
Now, Sean, you know she had no other choice.
我是说 不来这儿就得去少管所
I mean, it was either this or juvi hall,
我是说 你不能一惹了麻烦
I mean, you just can't keep
就四处搬家
moving away every time you get into trouble.
站着说话不腰疼
Worked for you.
听着 我们都不想这样
Look, neither of us asked for this.
但是我答应你妈妈了要照顾好你
But I promised your mom I'd take care of you.
所以你就照着我们的规定来
So you just go by the rules her and I agreed to,
- 我保证你没事 - 规定
- ...and I'm sure you'll manage just fine. - Rules?
是啊 规定 很简单的
Yeah, rules. Real simple.
你去上学 你上完学就回家
You go to school, you come back here right after.
我不想看见或者听说你靠近任意一辆车
And I don't want to see or hear about you anywhere near a car.
这儿 卧室归你
Here, the bedroom is yours.
随意点吧
Make yourself comfortable.
十点熄灯
Lights out in 10.
开玩笑吧
You got to be kidding.
- 我搭错车了 - 啊
- Wrong train. - Huh?
我是新来的
I'm new here.
我是博斯韦尔 老师
Boswell, yes, ma'am.
校内鞋
Uwabaki.
日本人吃的东西就像在军队里一样
Japanese food is like the Army.
不言而喻
Don't ask, don't tell.
在下外号黑闪 嘿 我发现你没有笔记本电脑啊
Name's Twinkie. Hey, I noticed you ain't have a laptop.
怎么
Yeah?
我给你弄一台 半价
I'll hook you up. Half price.
不用了 不需要
No, I'm cool.
四折怎么样 既然我们都是在军队里长大的
60% off. Since we're both army brats and everything.
兄弟 我可没钱啊
I ain't got no cash, man.
而且我不是军队里长大的
And I ain't an army brat.
好吧好吧 那你要不来个手机
All right, all right. Well, what about a cell phone, huh?
每个人都需要手机
Everybody needs a cell phone.
无意冒犯
No offense,
我可能在这儿待不了多长时间
but I'm probably not gonna
没准连你的名字都记不住
be here long enough to remember your name.
出门在外必须要买双好鞋啊 伙计
Then you gonna need some new shoes to book town with, man.
你喜欢迈克尔·乔丹吗 我爱死他了
You like Michael Jordan? I love Michael Jordan.
看看这双
Check this out.
最新款的乔丹鞋 现在还没上市
Brand new Jordans. Not even out yet.
连勒布朗·詹姆斯都没搞到
LeBron James couldn't even get his hands on those.
你还卖斯巴寇的方向盘吗
You selling that Sparco steering wheel?
当然不卖 这是我自己的
Hell, no. That's mine right there.
这可是我按零售价买的
Man, I even paid retail for it.
你开什么车
What you drive?
- 我的车 - 是啊
- My ride? - Yeah.
- 我的车可与众不同最时尚 - 带我看看去
- My ride's one of a kind. - Show me.
我还以为你在这儿待不了多久呢
Thought you weren't sticking around.
好吧
All right.
厉害吧 看看我的宝贝车
Slamming, huh? Look at that car.
哦吼
Ooh!
至少由我来开
At least let me drive.
你带我去的地方最好有几辆像样的车
Y'all better have some real cars around here.
好吧 你总算会说笑了 好吧
Okay, I see somebody got jokes, huh? Well, all right.
我不知道你到没到开车的年龄
I don't know if you're ready for them, though.
你看起来可有点小紧张
You look a little nervous.
你好吗 托什
What up, Tosh?
打飞机的时候用吧 兄弟
For when you blow your wad, man.
听到了吗
Hear that?
还是和我开车的方式不合适
It's still not right for the way I drive.
我不用电脑数据告诉我节流阀有什么反应
I don't need a computer to tell me about my throttle response.
那好吧 那就这样吧
Okay. Then we're done here.
引擎用V8就没问题了
You wouldn't have that problem with a V8.
男孩子啊
Boys.
他们只关心谁的引擎马力最大
All they care about is who's got the biggest engine.
我骨子里就是如假包换的男人
I'm a guy. It's in my DNA.
所以你们就用这种车比赛 对吧 可爱的小玩具
So y'all race with these things, huh? Cute little toys.
你没穿拖鞋 我差点没认出你
You know, I almost didn't recognize you without your slippers on.
你是说制轮器吧
Don't you mean uwabaki?
你叫妮拉 对吧
Neela, right?
学得挺快
You're a quick learner.
你从哪儿来
So, where you from, anyway?
这儿
Here.
不 我不是问你住哪儿 我是问你家乡是哪里的
No, I mean, not where you live. Where'd you come from?
这个问题很重要吗
Does it really matter where I'm from?
这个新来的小子是谁
Who's the tourist?
D 你什么时候开始在意那个学生妹了
What's with you and the schoolgirls, D?
红颜多祸水 你得提高你的品位
You're moving up in the world. You gotta elevate your company.
你是周三 周三 来和周四打个招呼
Wednesday, Wednesday, meet Thursday. God. Girl.
姑娘们 记住了啊
Ladies, hold that thought,
好吗 真棒 等我一下
all right? All right, beautiful. Hold up.
他正要走呢
He was just leaving.
抱歉 我不会说日语
I'm sorry. I don't speak Japanese.
看懂了吗 洋鬼子
Understand that'? Gaijin?
隆志
Takashi.
我们就聊聊天
We were just talking.
这不是你的地盘
This isn't your scene.
你刚才叫我“洋鬼子”还是什么的
That word you called me, gaijin or something or other,
那到底是什么意思
what does that mean exactly?
意思是 转过身
Means, turn around,
赶紧滚
keep walking.
我们这就准备走了 走吧 兄弟
That's exactly what we gonna do. Come on, man, let's roll.
嘿 听着 他就是无赖
Yo, look, man, he's yakuza.
挺有意思的
Now, see, that's funny,
我原以为这里是个自由的国度
'cause I thought this was, like, a free country
姑娘们可以想和谁聊天就和谁聊天
where a girl could talk to whoever she wants.
你知道我是谁吗 小子
You know who I am, boy?
知道 你就是日本的贾老板 不是吗
Yeah. You're like the Justin Timberlake of Japan, right?
走吧
Leave.
我去 兄弟 你知道无赖是什么意思吗 就像黑手党
Damn, man. You know yakuza? The Mafia?
听着 抱歉 DK先生 小猴子今天没吃到香蕉
Look, sorry, DK-san. Monkey didn't have his banana today.
嘿 D 我们走吧
Hey, D, let's go.
该比赛了
It's time to race.
贾老板 祝你好运啊
Good luck, Timberlake.
算你今天走运 因为我要去比赛了
You're the one that's lucky, 'cause I'm about to race.
那就比一场啊
Then let's race.
你拿什么跟我比 滑板吗
With what, huh? Your skateboard?
没车的时候怎么吹牛逼都行啊
Easy to sound cocky when you got no ride.
开我的
Take mine.
比一场吧
Let's race.
怎么了 我就想看看那孩子有什么本事
What? I wanna see what the kid's got.
他会开车吗
Can he drive?
会开车
你知道DK什么意思吗
You know what DK stands for?
大金刚
Donkey Kong?
漂移之王
Drift King.
漂移
Drift?
漂移是什么意思
What do you mean, drift?
还需要查查什么意思吗
Still need a dictionary?
你知道那张名画吗
You know that real famous painting?
就是有个女人一直微笑的那张
The one of the woman who's smiling all the time?
- 蒙娜丽莎 - 对对对 就是蒙娜丽莎
- The Mona Lisa. - Right, right, right. Mona Lisa.
听着 伙计
Well, look, man, this car right
这辆车就是漂移界的蒙娜丽莎
here's like the Mona Lisa of the drift world.
韩从基础部分改造重塑了这辆车
Han rebuilt this bad boy from ground up.
是经过改造的活塞
We talking forged pistons,
更大马力的发动机 新的牵引杆和机轴
bigger turbo, new rods, new crankshaft.
嘿 兄弟 韩可不是廉价劳动力 懂吗
Hey, man, Han's labor ain't cheap, man, you feel me?
好吧 我需要三十秒学学怎么漂移
Well, if I needed a 30-second lesson on how to drift...
好吧 听着兄弟
All right, look, man,
漂移有很多种方法 懂吗
there's lots of ways you can do this, all right?
手动刹车是最简单的
Hand braking is the easiest,
所以你要做的第一件事
so the first thing I want you to do,
就是猛拉手刹
I want you to rip that e-brake.
拉过手刹之后
All right, after you rip the e-brake,
把油门踩到底
then I want you to power over.
算了 你只要别毁了蒙娜丽莎就好
You know what? Just don't mess up Mona, all right?
出发
Go!
我告诉过你了
I told you.
我靠
Damn it!
喔 喔 喔
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
见鬼
Damn it!
别跑哦
Don't leave town.
你知道现在几点了吗
Do you know what time it is?
我以为才七点左右
I thought it was around 7:00.
美国时间要延后几个小时呢
You know, US is a few hours behind.
看起来这边的派对更好玩一点
Looks like the party was better here, anyway.
肖恩 你去飙车了是吗
Have you been racing, Sean?
你不能在这待下去了
You're out of here.
随你便
Go ahead.
你没明白 是吧
You don't get it, do you?
你已无处可去了
You have nowhere else to go.
如果在这儿都不行
If it doesn't work out here,
你就得去坐牢 懂吗
you're going to jail. Do you get that?
这不是游戏 我再告诉你一次
This isn't a game. And I'm gonna tell you one more time,
你要是想在我这儿住下去
if you're gonna live under my roof,
你就要遵守我的规则 要不你就给我滚
you're gonna go by my rules or get out.
懂了吗
Understand?
是的
Yes, sir.
上车吧
Get in.
我会赔钱给你的
I'll get you your money.
说得好像你不用赔钱似的
Why you talking like you have a choice?
里边有个带爪子的家伙欠我钱
There's a guy in there with a paw that owes me some money.
爪子
A Paw?
去把我的钱要回来
Go get me my money.
好吧
Okay.
韩说
Han said,
还钱
okane.
韩说 还钱
Han send, okane.
走吧
Let's go.
你现在开始做送货的工作
You're in the pickup and delivery business now.
只要我打电话给你 你就要随叫随到
I might call you once a week or once an hour.
我不管你是生病了还是在和碧昂斯滚床单
I don't care if you're sick as a dog or in bed with Beyonce.
叫你就得来
I call, you show.
- 除非你教我漂移 - 你没有讨价还价的余地
- Only if you teach me how to drift. - This ain't a negotiation.
我可没讨价还价
I wasn't negotiating.
他来这干什么
What's he doing here?
他来赔那辆放在我车库里
He's paying me back for
被撞坏的车的钱
that crumpled beer can sitting in my garage.
希望不是他开车
Hope he's not driving.
洋鬼子
Gaijin.
你下次什么时候比赛 我很想去看看
When is your next race? I'd really like to be there.
你为什么不参加呢
Why not be in it?
你真的是个小混蛋牛仔啊 还是就随口说说
You really a bad ass, cowboy, or you just talk like one?
你听见我的话了
You heard me.
还想再毁一辆车啊 韩
Ready to lose another car, Han?
我想要你那辆86年的卡罗拉
I'm ready to take that '86 Corolla off your hands.
好吧
All right.
拿你72年的天际线来赌
Put up the '72 Skyline.
成交
Done.
让他出去
Get him out of here.
我们要谈生意
We have business to discuss.
你的货来晚了
Your shipment's late.
你什么时候开始在意这些细节了
Since when are you so worried about the details?
韩 你的货什么时候到
When is the shipment arriving, Han?
别担心 我会去处理的
Just sit pretty and let me handle it.
嘿 爸 是我
Hey, Dad, it's me.
放学后我得多留一会 有课外活动
I had to stay after school for some extracurricular activities.
所以我会晚点到家
So I'll be home a little later.
再见
Sir.
你真的不能再跟着我了
You really need to stop following me around.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我想顺便过来
I thought I'd stop by and
向你男朋友学学漂移
ask your boyfriend for some drifting lessons.
相信我 你不想进入我们的圈子的
Trust me. You don't wanna be a part of this world.
你不是混得挺好的吗
It's good enough for you.
你一点都不了解我
You don't know anything about me.
你为什么觉得我不了解
Well, why don't you think I know?
因为我是个洋鬼子 是个外人
'Cause I'm a gaijin? An outsider?
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你是从军队里出身的 一直在搬家
You're an army brat who moved around a lot.
你爸妈从来不回家
Your mama and daddy was never home.
所以你到处闯祸
So you walked around pissed off all the time.
现在你把这些漂移族当成你的家人
And now you found your family with these drift nuts.
什么都没猜对 牛仔
Zero for one, cowboy.
你怎么不像其他白人一样
Why can't you go find a nice Japanese
找个可爱的日本姑娘呢
girl like the rest of the white guys around here?
一切没问题吧
Is everything okay back there?
我应付得了DK
I can handle DK.
我觉得他就是个黑社会无赖
I thought he's yakuza.
他叔叔确实是黑社会
His uncle's yakuza.
他只是在他的圈子里面做个小流氓
He's just playing gangster in his little storage room.
但是我需要他
But I need him.
他能让蒲田从我们这儿少讹点钱
He keeps Uncle Kamata from poking around too much.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他叔叔从他势力范围内的
Well, his uncle gets a
每个生意人身上都要提成
piece of the action from everyone on his turf.
我们也不例外
We're on his turf.
能留下一半总比什么都没有强
50% of something is better than 100% of nothing.
你和DK飙过车吗
So have you raced DK?
为什么不呢 他有那么厉害吗
Why not? Is he that good?
飙车比赛的关键是什么
What's the point of a race?
看看我是不是比其他人牛逼
To see if I'm better than the other guy.
只能证明你比别人快 仅此而已
Just proves you're faster, that's all.
如果我去比赛 那一定是为了很重要的事情
If I were to race, it would have to be for something important.
否则为什么要去做呢
Or why else do it at all?
为什么那天你让我参加比赛呢
Why are you letting me race?
因为你就是DK的克星
'Cause you're DK's kryptonite.
而且你欠我一辆车
And you owe me a car.
我靠
Oh, shit.
怎么回事
What the...
警车装置数据都是工厂里面调好的
Police cars here are only factory-tuned.
你要是跑到180码以上
You can do better than 180 k,
他们追不上你 所以干脆就不追了
they can't catch you, so they don't even try.
你知道吗 我开始喜欢这个国家了
You know what? I'm beginning to like this country already.
丹尼
Danny!
你看起来不错啊
You're looking good.
迪斯科
Disco.
我们得跟上 请你喝一杯
We gotta catch up. Get you a drink on me, huh?
来吧
Let's go.
啊哦
Uh-oh.
悠着点 姑娘们
Easy now, ladies.
来吧
Come on.
还好吗 你好吗
What's up? How you doing?
嘿 宝贝儿
Hey, baby.
姑娘们 放过那个小男孩 他还没成年呢
Keep your hands off the kid, girls. He's underage.
姑娘们 姑娘们 姑娘们 这简直是成人的迪斯尼乐园 是吧
Ladies, ladies, ladies. Disneyland for grownups, huh?
- 这些姑娘都是 看起来就像 - 像什么 模特吗
- All these girls, man, they look like... - What, models?
听我说
Check it out.
你看 东京就像是
See, Tokyo is the fashion
地球另一端的时尚之都 对吧
capital on this side of the planet, all right?
想象你已经搔首弄姿一整天了
Now, imagine you been posing all day.
那真是很困难的工作啊
I mean, that's a lot of hard work.
你不仅仅是感觉累了 最重要的是
Not only do you get tired, but, on top of that,
你想找点乐子
you wanna have a little fun,
但是你不能 因为你在城里谁都不认识
but you can't 'cause you don't even know nobody in town.
这边的大多数家伙
And most of the guys around here
胆子太小都不敢勾搭姑娘
are too chicken shit to even try picking up one.
那你该怎么办
So what do you do?
兄弟 你得认识能让你开心的人啊
Man, you talk to the little dude who makes you laugh.
对吧
Yeah.
听着 兄弟 我不仅不受拘束 我还打破陈规
Look, man, I don't just think outside the box. I tear it up.
这才是我
That's my thing.
哟
Yo!
肖恩
Sean!
红色的三菱是给你的
The red Evo's yours.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你现在就代表我
You're representing me now.
你觉得我会让你开辆破现代吗
What you think, I'm gonna let you roll in a Hyundai?
噢 老天
Oh, man.
该死
Damn it.
我妈妈 瞎了一只眼
My mother, she's blind in
她漂移都比这个强
one eye and she can drift better than that.
韩 你从哪找到这小子的
Han, where did you find this guy?
谁来教教他怎么漂移
Will someone please teach this guy how to drift?
是你的车吗
Is that yours?
是啊
Sure is.
怎么回事
What happened?
我不知道 我在地下室发现的时候就这样了
I don't know. I found it this way at the base.
还是能修好的
It's got potential.
也许是 走着看吧
Yeah, maybe. We'll see.
肖恩 日本人常说
You know, Sean, the Japanese have a saying.
“枪打出头鸟”
"The nail that sticks out gets hammered."
你上学要迟到了
You're gonna be late.
肖恩
Sean!
不可能 是你自己弄坏的
Come on, man, you broke it.
嘿 喔 喔
Hey, whoa, whoa.
一定有误会
There must be a misunderstanding.
滚开 否则你就是下一个挨打的
Out of my way, or you're next.
- 冷静点 - 听着 伙计 我这不能退货
- Take it easy. - Look, man, I don't do refunds, all right?
上啊 来啊
Okay, let's go, then! Let's go!
你再敢碰我一下
Touch me again...
给你
Here.
别再把这个弄坏了
Try not to break this one.
你是不是脑子有毛病啊
Say, man! What the hell is wrong with you, huh?
现在谁都想到我这来退货了
Now everybody's gonna want exchanges around here.
见鬼
Damn!
做英雄也不容易啊 是吗
Not easy saving the day, is it?
也许你有时候可以给我点建议
Maybe you could give me some pointers sometime.
你做得对
You're doing all right.
谢谢
Thanks.
嘿
Hey.
怎么
Yeah?
那天晚上很抱歉
Sorry about the other night.
你的生活与我无关
Your life isn't any of my business.
没关系
It's okay.
犯规
Foul!
- 我才没犯规 - 你犯规了
- Ain't no damn foul. - That was a foul.
- 你挡着我了 - 你犯规了
- Yo, you in my face. - That was a foul.
嘿 韩 把这个烂人轰出去
Hey, Han, sort this wanker out.
烂人
A wanker?
那我像什么 斑马吗
What do I look like, a zebra?
你怎么会选择在这里生活
So, how did you end up over here, anyway?
你知道以前的西部地区
Well, you know those old Westerns
牛仔们都会奋力跑过边界吗
where the cowboys make a run for the border?
这里就是我的墨西哥
This is my Mexico.
为什么让我开你的车比赛
Why'd you let me race with your car?
你知道我会撞坏的
You knew I was gonna wreck it.
为什么不呢
Why not?
因为会浪费一大笔钱
'Cause it's a lot of money.
我有的是钱
I have money.
我需要周围有我能信得过的人
It's trust and character I need around me.
选好了身边的人
You know, who you choose
才能让你更了解自己
to be around you lets you know who you are.
一辆车可以换来对自己的认知
And one car in exchange for knowing what a man's made of,
我觉得很划算
that's a price I can live with.
你看看下面那些人
Look at all those people down there.
他们循规蹈矩是为了什么
They follow the rules, for what?
他们让恐惧引领着他们的生活
They're letting fear lead them.
如果他们不这么做会怎么样呢
What happens if they don't?
生活很简单 做出选择就不回头
Life's simple. You make choices and you don't look back.
那么 如果你漂移不是为了赢得比赛 那你为什么要漂移呢
So, if you don't drift to win, what do you drift for?
- 你真的想知道吗 - 是啊
- You really want to know? - Yeah.
好 跟我来
Okay. Let's go.
漂移要持之以恒
There's no "Wax on, wax off" With drifting.
边做边学
Learn by doing it.
发明漂移的人
The first drifters invented
从这山路上来感受它
drifting out here in the mountains by feeling it.
你也感觉一下吧
So feel it.
再来
Again!
- 包里放什么了 - 等会你就知道了
- What's in this bag? - You'll see.
- 你有多少 - 有的是呢 多来点吧
- How much you got? - Keep going, keep going.
我爽翻了 兄弟 我都能把避孕套卖给和尚了
I'm so good, man, I could sell rubbers to a monk.
再来
Again.
别着急 别着急 不要太早 就现在
Watch it. Watch it. Not too early, now.
快 快 快
Go, go, go, go!
别松开 别松开
Don't lose it! Don't lose it!
嘿 韩
Hey Han...
看看这个
Take a look at this.
有人来看你了
You have a visitor.
嘿 黑闪 给他准备个位置
Hey, Twink. Get this man a bunk.
合作愉快
Pleasure doing business.
耶 宝贝 我告诉过你 对吗
Yeah, baby. I told you. I told you, didn't I?
其实还不错 我番茄酱都还没放呢
It's actually not bad. I didn't even have to put ketchup on it.
看吧 我不是个完完全全的洋鬼子
See, I'm not a total gaijin.
我讨厌这个词
I hate that word. It's
从小我就被人这么叫
what they used to call me when I was a kid.
我以为你是在这出生的
I thought you were born here.
“外人”有很多不同的意义
Well, "Outsider" Can mean many different things.
我妈妈在我十岁那年就去世了
My mom died when I was 10.
她高中毕业之后就从澳大利亚到了日本
She came out here from Australia when she finished high school.
我只知道
And all I know about her
她去做了酒吧的舞女
is that she went to work in a hostess bar.
DK的祖母收留了我
DK's grandmother took me in.
好吧 我父母在我三岁的时候离婚了
Well, my parents split up when I was three.
我和我妈妈总是搬家 主要是因为我
Me and Mom moved around a lot. Mostly 'cause of me.
好吧 全都是因为我
Well, it was all 'cause of me.
我总是让我自己变成外人
Kind of made myself an outsider, you know,
想都没想过
without even thinking about it.
但是现在我意识到了外人还是本地人 其实都不重要
But I realize now, outsider or insider, it doesn't really matter.
重要的是要知道自己心中真正想要的
All that matters is knowing what you really want
并且为之努力
and going after it.
我们小的时候经常到这来
We used to come up here when we were kids.
甚至不到开车年龄的时候就翘课溜出来
Even before we could drive we'd cut class, sneak out,
到这来看大一点的孩子漂移
come up here, and watch the older kids drift.
那时候情况不一样
Things were different back then.
当我一拿到驾照 我就在这扎根了
Once I got my license, I practically lived up here.
那时候 孩子们什么车都敢开
Back then, kids just drove whatever they had.
我们只是自娱自乐 没有人打扰我们
You know, we just made do. No one bothered us.
我拿到驾照的那一天
The day I got my license
就是我第一次拿到超速罚单的那天
is the day I got my first speeding ticket.
第二天 我赢了人生中第一场比赛
The day after that, I won my first race.
我赢了那个富二代三个车身的距离
I beat this rich kid by three lengths.
我得承认那感觉爽呆了
I gotta admit, it felt good.
就像
It felt like...
其他的一切都消失了
Like everything else just disappears.
- 没有过去没有将来 - 没有烦恼
- No past and no future. - No problems.
只有那个时刻
Just the moment.
他需要降降温了
Boy needs to chill.
嘿 黑闪 我还要一套轮胎
Hey, Twink, I'm gonna grab another set.
喔 喔喔喔 还要一套
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa! Another set?
不行 听着 今天都三套了
No. Look, that was your third set today.
轮胎可不便宜
I mean, them tires ain't cheap.
DK 坐吧 我们来烤点蘑菇吃
DK, grab a chair. We're about to roast some marshmallows.
哟 冷静点 伙计
Yo, come on, man, look...
离她远点
Stay away from her,
要不你能开的东西就只有轮椅了
or the only thing you'll be driving is a wheelchair.
找个新车手吧
Find yourself a new driver.
- 我没事 - 你到底想怎样
- I'm all right. - What'd you expect?
你不仅在玩火
You didn't just play with fire,
这都引火烧身了
you soaked the matches in gasoline.
都结束了
It's over.
- 就因为那个洋鬼子 - 我就是个洋鬼子
- All this over a gaijin? - I am a gaijin.
你变了 DK
You've changed, DK.
你说我变了
You say I've changed.
但是你和我也没什么不同
But we're not so different, you and I.
我们都是私生子 不是吗
We're both products of screw ups, aren't we?
他们说你妈妈
They say your mom was the best trick
是那时候歌舞伎町最棒的舞娘
in all of Kabukicho back in the day.
别把我妈妈扯进来
Leave my mother out of this.
如果我们没有收留你 你就跟她一样了
If we hadn't taken you in, you'd be just like her,
为了挣钱可以做任何事
doing anything for a buck.
人们愿意跟随你
Think anyone would take a
还不是因为你有个叔叔
second look at you if it wasn't for your uncle?
我们都是一样的 妮拉
We're the same, Neela.
不同的是我知道我是谁 属于哪里
Difference is I know who I am and where I belong.
你知道你是谁吗
Do you know who you are?
你知道你属于哪里吗
Do you know where you belong?
嘿
Hey.
进来吧
Come on.
嘿 兄弟
Hey, brother.
我为你担保 我用我的名誉在给你担保
I vouched for you! Put my reputation on the line for you!
我们是搭档
We were partners!
你怎么能背后搞小动作坑我
You think you can keep your side deals from me?
别这样 我们都不是小孩了
Come on. We ain't in the Boy Scouts.
- 这再正常不过了 - 隆志
- This is what we do. - Takashi!
现在怎么样
What about now?
嗯
Hmm?
这也是正常的吗
Is this what we do?
伙计 你需要我
Man, you need me.
如果不是有我在
You'd still be shaking down
你还在敲诈茶室赚钱吧
tea houses for chump change if it wasn't for me.
- 上车 - 快 快 快
- Get in! - Go! Go! Go!
快点
Come on.
肖恩 肖恩
Sean, Sean!
隆志
Takashi.
如果我是你 我就不会这么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
好吧
Okay.
我跟你走
I'll go with you.
妮拉
Neela.
等你爸比不在的时候咱们再聊
See you when Daddy's not around.
- 我今天晚上就会把你送上飞机 - 爸
- I'm putting you on a plane tonight. - Dad...
肖恩 别跟我吵
Sean, don't argue with me.
这是我的错 我不能一走了之
I did this. I can't run away.
我不能
I can't.
肖恩 我是你父亲 我要对你的行为负责
Sean, I'm your father. I'm responsible for your well-being.
我也要为我自己犯的错负责
And I'm responsible for my mess.
我要去弥补
I gotta do this.
你能明白吗
Can you understand that?
至少你没有重蹈我的覆辙
At least you're not redoing my mistakes.
伙计 你还好吗
You all right, man?
我们得离开这个城市 听着 我认识一些人
We're leaving town. Look, I know some people...
我不能跑 黑闪
I can't do it, Twink.
听着 DK要杀了你
Look, DK wants your head.
懂吗
All right?
你把麻烦惹到蒲田头上了 你完蛋了 兄弟
And the trouble you just made for Kamata? You're done here, bro.
- 也许我该直接和蒲田聊聊 - 什么
- Maybe I should talk to Kamata. - What?
DK都听他的
DK answers to him.
我就当我刚才什么都没听见
I know I just didn't hear that.
我要结束这一切 我必须要和他谈谈
I gotta end this. I'm gonna go talk to him.
你疯了吗
What, are you crazy, huh?
韩死了 好吗
Han is dead, all right!
而且 你不能就这么直愣愣的走到蒲田的地盘
Plus, you can't just walk into Kamata's place, man!
我只有这一个办法
It's all I got.
韩应该想要你带上这些
Something I think Han would've wanted you to have.
这是什么
What's this?
如果你想活着从蒲田的地盘出来
You're gonna need it if
你会需要这些的
you're gonna make it out of Kamata's place alive.
你不需要吗
Don't you need it?
不 不用了 我自己可以解决
No, it's cool. Look, I'll figure it out.
肖恩
Sean.
你快走
You need to leave.
你来错地方了
You came to the wrong place.
我不是来见你的
I didn't come here to see you.
你以为
You think
你可以走进来 撇下这些钱然后就走出去
you can walk in here, dump some cash and walk out?
首先我只是想把你的东西
I know I'm only returning
还给你 蒲田先生
what belonged to you in the first place, sir.
但是我不是为了这个来的
But that's not why I really came.
我是来道歉的
I came here to apologize.
我知道你的侄子和我有些小矛盾
I know your nephew and I have embarrassed ourselves badly.
先生 我到这里来 是为了向您提供一个和平的解决方案
Sir, I'm here to offer you a peaceful solution.
你想怎么办
How do you plan to accomplish that?
比赛
A race.
我和DK给你还有所有人带来了麻烦
DK and I have caused nothing but problems for you, for us.
我请求你允许我们自己解决 一劳永逸
And I'm asking you to allow us to settle this, once and for all.
我们比赛
We race
输的人永远离开这里
and the loser leaves town for good.
我已经赢过你这个孬种一次了
I've already beat this piece of shit once!
很好
Good.
那就简单了
Then it should be easy.
警察把所有车都拖走了
The cops took all the cars.
嘿
Hey!
这就是它不行的原因
That's why she's spitting.
就快好了 再调试几次就行
We almost there, Twink. Couple more tweaks.
我担心的不是车 伙计
It's not the car I'm worried about, man.
DK选择这条路是有原因的 这是他的山
DK picked this road for a reason. This is his mountain.
他是唯一一个能从头开到尾的
He's the only one to ever make it to the bottom.
耶
Yeah!
- 耶 - 干得好
- Yeah! - Yes!
来啊
Come on.
好样的 加油
Yeah! Come on!
- 加油 肖恩 - 冲啊 冲啊
- Come on, Sean. - Let's go! Let's go!
肖恩 你最牛逼 加油
Sean, you the boss. Let's go.
我靠 挺住啊 兄弟 这不对啊
Damn! Come on, man! That ain't right.
耶 肖恩 我就说嘛
Yeah, baby! That's what I'm talking about, man.
我就说嘛
I told you!
你们可以走了
You're free to go.
嘿哟 肖恩 哟 肖恩
Hey, yo, Sean! Yo, Sean!
嘿 快来看啊 兄弟
Hey, check this out, man.
有个家伙要和新漂移王赛车
This dude over here wanna race the new DK.
听说他在亚洲所向披靡啊
Heard he's been beating everybody around Asia, too.
今晚不行 黑闪
Not tonight, Twinkie.
他说他认识韩
Said he knew Han.
说韩是他的家人
Said Han was family.
好吧
All right.
来比一场
Let's race.
车不错啊
Nice ride.
几年前从韩那赢来的
I won it from my friend Han, a few years ago.
我都不知道他喜欢美国老爷车
I didn't know he was into American muscle.
他和我一起混的时候就喜欢
He was when he was rolling with me.
这可不是十秒跑四分之一英里的比赛
You know this ain't no 10-second race.
我有的是时间
I got nothing but time.
准备好了吗 小子
You ready, kid?
加油 肖恩 加油
Come on, Sean! Come on!
各就位
Ready!
预备
Set!
出发
Go!